本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：侯默   Soomii   红豆包   Iz   Ｊ小糯
校对：stephanie      时间轴：鱼骨头
■
后期：鱼骨头      总监：stephanie
吉恩
Gene.
吉恩  吉恩
Gene. Gene.
什么事
What?
别弄了
Stop.
鲍勃  别再看报纸了  行么
Bob, no more newspaper, please.
我父母快要来了
My parents are gonna be here any minute.
我知道
I know.
你猜我怎么知道他们要来的
You know how I know they're coming?
因为每次你都会疯狂地打扫
Because you go into a crazy cleaning frenzy every time.
就像动物在地震前惊恐万分四处逃窜一样
It's like the way animals freak out before an earthquake.
很好  此话非事实
That's nice. That's not true.
她被吓坏了
She's spooked.
露易丝  你把麦片弄得到处都是
Louise, you're gettin' cereal everywhere.
我犯抽风病了
I'm having a seizure!
赶紧塞我嘴里一个钱包
Put a wallet in my mouth!
没事了
It passed.
看看这个地方  一团糟
Look at this place. It's a disaster.
屋顶漏水你还没修
You haven't even fixed the leak yet.
好啦  琳达  罐子很给力
Come on. Linda, the leak is contained.
-老鲍  -怎么了
- Bobby! - What?
是你太在意了
You barely notice those.
我没事
I'm ok.
听我说  鲍勃
Trust me, Bobby.
我老妈肯定会注意到屋顶在漏水
My mother will notice that our ceiling is leaking.
没错  你说的对
yeah, you're right.
她会注意到  连墨迹带大喊大叫
She will, repeatedly and loudly.
修好它吧  拜托
Just fix it, please.
做全美无所不能工匠男  我亲爱的小鲍
Be my all-American fix-it man, Bobby.
好吧  我到阁楼去修理一下
Fine. I'll go up to the attic and fix the leak.
同时我要你跟孩子们讨论一下
But I also need you and the kids to work out
应该让哪间房出来给我父母睡
Whose room my folks are sleepin' in,
因为我得去检查浴室里有没有掉发
Because I have to go check the bathroom for stray hairs.
我们家脱发问题太严重
No one sheds like this family.
就像一群多毛怪
It's like a bunch of chewbaccas.
姥姥和姥爷睡哪间房
So where are grandma and grandpa gonna sleep?
吉恩的房太臭
Gene's room smells like farts.
说的在理
That makes sense.
太好了  让他们住那间房
Great. Well, we'll put 'em in there, then.
他们闻到放屁的味道  或许很快就走了
Maybe they'll leave sooner when they smell farts.
-大好  -吉恩可以跟我睡一间房
- Yeah. - Gene can sleep with me in my room
只要他不介意我晚上会发恶梦
As long as he doesn't mind my night terrors. Huh?
记得  在我八岁的时候
Remember, you let me watch
该片是罗梅罗大师的经典之作  正是该片改变了丧尸电影的格局
成为了恐怖片中的里程碑  丧尸恐怖片的转折点
是你让我看"活死人之夜"
"Night of the living dead" When I was 8,
然后我每晚都会被吓醒  站在房间的正中央
So now I wake up every night standing in the middle of my room,
狂抓乱踢
Scratching the air, and kicking.
不错  等等  你现在还会那样
Oh, good. Wait. You still get those?
-是  而且动作越来越奇怪  -上帝啊
- Yeah. They're weirder now. - Oh, boy.
我想我潜意识下的恐惧和性萌芽
I think my subconscious fears and my budding sexuality
交错在一起
are getting all mixed up.
我... 蒂娜  我不想知道
Ok, I... Tina, I don't want to hear it.
所以我会觉得我被僵尸攻击
So I think I'm being attacked by zombies,
然后我会大叫  "想亲热下吗"
And I start screaming, "Do you wanna make out?"
然后我跟它亲热
And I make out with it.
我想我还是跟姥姥和姥爷凑合睡吧
I might just bunk with gram and gramps.
够了
Ok, enough.
吉恩  露易丝  你们睡蒂娜的房间
Gene, Louise, you sleep in Tina's room.
蒂娜  你得被隔离  你一个人睡
Tina, you're quarantined. You sleep alone.
我们要先把你绑起来或者想些其他的办法
We'll strap you down or something.
留下嘴能亲热就行
Leave my lips free.
吉恩  只是姥姥和姥爷要来
Gene, just 'cause grandma and grandpa are comin',
不代表你可以不用做作业
Doesn't mean you're gonna get out of doin' homework.
你那个历史报告写了多少
How far are you on that history report?
目前  只是写了标题
So far, I just got the title...
历史: 来自过去的一声巨响
History: A blast from the past."
好吧  等我们把姥姥  姥爷安顿好后
Ok. After we get my parents settled,
你爸爸会帮你做的  对吗  鲍勃
Your father's gonna help you with that. Right, Bob?
五点前写好放在我桌上
Have it on my desk by 5:00.
我不会替你写报告
I am not writing your report for you.
好吧  大家听着
Hey! Ok, everybody,
我有几句话要说
I have an announcement to make.
我在梯子上  别撞它
I am on a ladder. Stop shaking it.
我本以为  不需要提醒你们
I feel like I shouldn't have to say that.
老爸  为什么格罗瑞娅姥姥
Dad, why do you get so mad when grandma Gloria
和艾尔姥爷一来你就变得这么生气
And grandpa Al come over to visit?
你讨厌他们吗
Do you hate them?
我不讨厌他们  只是你姥姥
I don't hate them. Just grandma.
不是讨厌她本人  只是讨厌她的弄出的声音
Or I don't hate her, just the sound she makes
还有她的嗓音和说的话
And her voice and the things she says.
艾尔
Al!
想听下我对她的印象吗
Wanna hear my impression of her?
想
Yes.
艾尔
Al!
我没听错吧
I'm not hearing this, right?
对不起  我是说  她是你姥姥
Sorry. I mean, she's your gram gram.
我们爱她
We love her.
我们讨厌她
we hate her.
漏水修好了
I fixed the leak!
好  别呆在那太久
Good! Don't stay up there too long,
因为在我们开店之前
'cause I wanna sorta have a nice visit
我想他们好好参观下
Before we open the restaurant!
我是说  快要修好了
Uh, I mean, almost done!
什么
Huh?
太神奇了
Wow. This is amazing.
这后面是谁的房间
Eh, whose room am I behind?!
我的
Mine.
你好  蒂娜
Hi, Tina.
你在墙里面还是在我的大马海报里面
Are you in the wall or in my horse poster?
拜托你跟我说  "在海报里"
Please say, "Horse poster."
我是只马
I'm a horse.
慢着  我还可以四处走走
Oh, wait. I can go sideways, too.
你在另一个空间里吗
Are you in another dimension?
"纳尼亚传奇"系列丛书第一部
有没看见  一个狮子  女巫  魔衣厨
Do you see a lion or a witch or a wardrobe?
一个什么
A what?
一个狮子  女巫  魔衣厨
A lion, a witch, or a wardrobe!
为什么这么说  吉恩
Why are you saying that, Gene?
这是一本书名
It's a book.
懂了  懂了  儿童书
Oh, right, right. A kid's book.
作者  萨尔曼・拉什迪
Yeah, by Salman Rushdie.
不是萨尔曼・拉什迪写的
It's not by Salman Rushdie.
-当然是他写的  -不是
- Of course it is. - It isn't.
是他写的
Yes, it is.
我不跟你争了  吉恩
I'm not gonna talk to you anymore, Gene.
我在墙里  不信你去翻书查查吧
I'm in a wall. Go look it up, though.
我刚查了  是萨尔曼・拉什迪
I just did. It's Salman Rushdie.
他们到了
They're here!
鲍勃  从墙里出来
Bob, come out of the wall, please!
好吧
Yeah.
大家好
Hello!
-艾尔  -天妈爷啊
- Al! - Oh, my god.
别把我们的包扔街上
Don't leave our bags out there on the street.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
这些锅碗瓢盆在地上干什么用的
What are all these pots doing on the floor?
鲍勃会把他们捡起来  妈妈
Bob'll pick 'em up, mom.
鲍勃  别再那里傻逛了
Bob, quit foolin' around in there.
你会被困在里面
You're gonna get yourself stuck.
琳  琳
Lin! Lin!
干什么  怎么了
Yes? What?
你肯定不会相信这个
You're never gonna believe this.
怎么了  什么
What is it? What?
我被困住了
I'm stuck!
早知道不应该放屁
Shouldn't have farted.
谁困在墙里
Who's trapped in the wall?
-鲍勃  -我
- Bob.  - Me.
鲍勃在墙里肯定不行
Bob can't fit in the wall.
他超重啊
He's overweight.
-拜托  妈妈  -什么
- Mom. - What?
他听不见我说的话
He can't hear me.
我可以听见  我就在这里
Yes, I can. I'm right here.
我想点个汉堡
I'd like to order a hamburger.
不行  艾尔  他不能吃汉堡
No, Al! He can't have a hamburger.
他可以吃火鸡汉堡
He can have a turkey burger.
没有火鸡汉堡这种东西
There's no such thing as a turkey burger.
比较温和的男性情色杂志  以更多的消遣内容为主
去读读你的"格言"吧
Go read your "Maxim."
爸爸看"格言"
Dad gets "Maxim"?
没有  他在公寓整理杂物时发现的这本书
No. He found it in the recycling at the condo.
封面女郎是谁
Who's on the cover?
"女狼俱乐部"美国喜剧片
剧中的四位女服务生以及美艳女老板个个身怀绝技
"女狼俱乐部"里面的女郎
The girls of "Coyote ugly."
她们应该不在这个世上了吧
I don't think they're even alive anymore.
琳  我们需要重开餐馆
Lin, we need to open the restaurant.
我确定我可以走去那里
Hey, I bet I can get down there.
你在说什么  你可以走下去吗
What are you talking about? You can go down?
孩子们  在下面等我  好吗
Kids, you meet me down there, ok?
你们就是我的眼睛和双手
You're gonna be my eyes and my hands.
好的  我们已经到了
Ok. We're down there.
没有  你们没有到  你们一步都没动
No, you're not. You haven't moved!
我在烧烤呢
I'm turning on the grill! Beep boop. Whoosh!
那不是烧烤时发出的声音
That's not the sound the grill makes.
到下面的餐馆去
Go down to the restaurant.
今天带来与众不同的乳酪汉堡
Ok, so the special comes with feta cheese,
它不是真正意义上的乳酪
And it's called never been feta.
你听到了吗  你在笑吗
Heh. Did you hear that? Are you laughing?
我听见你在笑  你在写下来吗
I hear you laughing. Are you writing it?
是啊  不是真正意义上的乳酪
Yep. Never been feta.
乳酪汉堡
很好  我要让蒂娜去准备烧烤
Good. All right, I'm gonna go get Tina set up on the grill.
一切进展顺利
This is going great!
孩子们  吉恩  露易丝
Hey, kids! Gene! Louise!
拿着  这是我的尿
Take this. That's my pee.
倒掉然后拿回来
Empty it out and bring it back, ok?
以后就这么循环下去
This'll be our system.
你是负责帮我倒尿的人
Uh... You're my pee guy.
老爸的尿
Dad's pee.
鲍勃  我已经打电话给承包商泰迪了
Ohh. Bob, I called Teddy the contractor!
他正在赶过来  把你弄出来
He's coming right away to get you out!
什么  琳  不用这么麻烦
What? No. Lin, that's not necessary.
显然这很有必要
Of course it is.
你困在了墙里
You're stuck in the wall.
不  我知道  你知道泰迪这个人
No, I know. Just you know how Teddy is.
唠叨的泰迪  没完没了
Talky Teddy, yap yap yap.
你没时间听他的故事吗
What, you don't have time for his stories?
你今天非常  非常的忙吗
Are you very, very busy today?
没有
Uh, no.
老鲍  你被卡住了  是吗
You're in a tight spot, huh, Bobby?
差点儿  泰迪
A little bit, Teddy.
我听说过这样的房子
Ehh. I've heard of buildings like this, you know,
墙的位置不对
With false walls. Uh-huh.
这是明令禁止的行为
It's a prohibition thing. Oh.
这个小镇曾经是一个走私港口
Yeah, this town, it used to be a bootleggers port.
很多人不知道这个
A lot of people don't know that.
听起来很有趣
That's interesting.
我的叔叔曾今在城镇经营一家地下酒吧
Yeah. My great-uncle used to run a speakeasy here in town.
他叫做斯万奇酒店  那地方也叫斯万奇
It was called Swanky's, place called Swanky's.
你听过有一种鸡尾酒叫做"偷鸡摸狗"吗
You ever hear of a cocktail called the swanky-panky?
-没听过  -它是由两种开胃酒
- No. - It's made with 2 parts vermouth...
泰迪  泰迪  泰迪  听着
Teddy. Teddy. Teddy, listen.
今天就不要把我弄出去了  好吗
Don't get me out today, ok?
去告诉琳达你明天再来
Tell Linda you have to come back tomorrow.
Milwaukee Ax Sawzall Blade"密尔沃基Sawzall斧刃"
又称"往复锯"通常被用于快速拆除工作
我卡车里有"往复锯"  我还没
I got the sawzall in the truck. I don't even...
不  不  不  泰迪  听着
No, no, no. Teddy, listen.
告诉她你需要许可证之类的东西
Tell her that you need a permit or something.
鲍勃  你想呆在墙里面吗
You want to stay in the wall, Bob?
泰迪  不要再猜了  不要猜了
Don't judge, Teddy. Don't judge.
一个人在这里舒服的爬行
There's nothing wrong with a man enjoying his crawl space
等待他老丈母娘和老丈人走  没什么不对
Till his in-laws leave.
不是  只是  我听说过一个人
No. It's just, you know, I heard about this guy
他躲在墙里以此来躲避警察的追捕
That hid out in a wall from the police.
鲍勃  他后来疯了
He went bonkers, Bob.
当他们发现他的时候
You know, when they found him,
2x4是木材的一种标准尺寸  一般只用于内墙
内墙的厚度一般是4寸左右
他嘴里嚼着一块2X4的木块
He was chewin' on a 2x4,
什么都没穿  身上缠满了铜线
Wearin' nothin' but copper wire.
泰迪  这个故事很不错
That's a great story, Teddy.
明天再回来
Just come back tomorrow.
好吧  但是今天的工钱还得收
Ok. I still gotta charge you for today, though.
今天  你就一直站在那里讲话
Today? You just stood there talking.
鲍勃  我的医生告诉我
Bob, you know, my therapist says
如果我不珍惜自己的时间
that if I don't value my time,
那么别人也不会珍惜
nobody's goin' to.
-好吧  你是对的  -好吧
- All right. You're right. - Right. Just...
好吧  先写个欠条
All right. I'm just gonna write it up
作为凭证  没有朋友价
as a consultation. No friend prices.
好吧  你想做什么就做什么
All right, do whatever you have to do
把欠条从通道口扔下来
And just drop the bill down the shaft.
好的
All right.
你拿到了吗
Did you get it?
你扔了吗
Did you drop it?
我扔了
I dropped it.
我没有拿到
I didn't get it.
我不能...  不能不收工钱
Well, I can't have the... you know, the things outstanding.
-泰迪  我会找  好吗  -找吧
- Teddy, I'll look for it, all right? - Find it.
再写张欠条
Write another one, then!
我没有...  现在我要回卡车里了
I don't have... now I gotta go to the truck.
正如你所见
Ok, as you can see,
今天是我在自己家房子的
I'm spending my first night
墙壁里面度过的第一个夜晚
Inside the walls of my own house.
我借了吉恩的摄影机
I borrowed Gene's camera
这样我可以把我的经验记录下来留给后人
so I can document my experience.
拜托  鲍勃  现在很晚了
Come on, Bob. It's late.
露易丝把她的酷奇・酷毙夜明灯借给我
And Louise has loaned me her Kuchi Kupi night light.
是酷奇・科比
Kuchi Kopi.
酷奇・科比  酷奇・科比娃娃夜光灯
Kuchi Kopi. Kuchi Kopi night light.
不管怎么样  我今晚将睡那里
Anyway, here's where I'm gonna sleep tonight.
给你们展示一下
I'll show you.
艾尔  爽
Oh, Al. Yes.
天哪
Oh, my god.
天哪  我想琳达的父母正在做爱
Oh, my god. I think Linda's parents are having sex.
希望他们戴套了
I hope they're using protection.
因为我可不想照顾那婴儿
'cause I am not taking care of that baby.
我要取个样儿
I'm gonna sample it.
你好
Well, hello.
你看起来真滑稽
Funny seeing you here.
一下来了两个
Whoa. Double trouble.
我们开始吧
Ok, let's do this.
你听起来像我姥姥
You sound like my grandmother.
什么  我听不见你说话
what? I can't hear you.
而你听起来像我姥爷
And you sound like my grandfather.
请不要再抚摸彼此了  请不要再抚摸彼此了
Please stop touching each other. Please stop touching each other.
第二天  距格罗瑞娅姥姥离开还有五个小时
吉恩  你准备好做报告了吗
Gene, you ready to give your report?
历史报告  今天到期
禁酒时期  1920-1933年间美国以法律
禁止酿酒及售酒的时期/妇女参政权论者
我的祖父母和我们住在一起
My grandparents are staying with us,
他们亲身经历了禁酒时期
and they were both alive during prohibition.
所以这听起来就像
So this is what it sounds like
他们在我隔壁做爱的声音
when they have sex in the room next to mine.
什么
What? Oww.
给我去校长办公室  现在就去
Principal's office! Now!
太好了
O-o-oww oww! Right.
父亲  在生活中  这个餐厅就是你的祸水
Father, in life, this restaurant was your curse.
现在  在死亡面前  你不得安息的灵魂在这里阴魂不散
Now, in death, your restless spirit haunts this place.
和我们说句话吧  父亲
Speak to us, father!
露易丝  是你吗
Louise, is that you?
你们听到了吗
Did you hear that?
是的  是我  你的女儿露易丝
Yes. It's Louise! Your daughter!
回到光明世界吧  父亲
Go to the light, father!
好吧  我明白了  很可笑  我成了鬼魂
Oh, ok, I see. Very funny. I'm a ghost.
想知道关于那边世界的任何问题  随便问
Ask him anything you wanna know about the other side.
你是来自电影"人鬼情未了"中的鬼魂吗
Are you the ghost from the movie "Ghost"?
不是  露易丝已经告诉过你们我是他已世父亲的鬼魂
No. Louise already told you I'm the ghost of her dead dad.
继续  下一个问题
Come on. Next question.
你是来自电影"鬼爸爸"中的鬼魂吗
Are you the ghost from the movie "Ghost dad"?
我刚才说什么来着
What did I just say?
这就是你们要问鬼魂的问题吗
This is what you ask a ghost?
你们知道这会让我想干嘛吗
You know what this makes me wanna do?
吃掉你们的灵魂
Eat your souls!
快跑
Run!
天啊  他抓住我了
Oh, god! He got me!
起码你现在确实吸引住我了
At least you're holding me now.
这里发生了什么事
What is going on over here?
对不起  琳
Uh, sorry, Lin.
真高兴你玩得这么开心
Well, I'm glad you're enjoying yourself.
我要过去打理厨房的事情了
I'll go back to running the kitchen,
看校车接送学生表  还要照顾孩子们
busing tables, and taking care of the kids.
天爷啊  琳  别生气
Oh, boy. Lin, don't be mad.
-到这来  -不
- Come here. - No.
到我手这边来
Come over toward my hand.
好吧  好吧
All right. All right.
让我以你喜欢的方式轻抚你的秀发
Let me stroke your hair the way you like.
舒服吗
Isn't this nice?
天吗
Oh, god.
对不起  抱歉
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
琳达  你那样简直就是你老妈在请嗓子
Linda, that's your mom's throat clear exactly.
那又怎么样
Yes. And?
第一  你的声音很像她
Well, first you make sounds like her.
其次  你会嚷道"不要汉堡  读读你的'格言'"
Next thing, you'll be yelling, "No burgers. Read your 'Maxim.'"
我是说  你已经开始学她一样唠叨了
I mean, you already kind of nag like she does. Whoop.
头发呢
Where's the hair?
我不会变成我老妈
I am not turning into my mother!
洗手间脏死了
That bathroom is filthy.
谁最后上的厕所
Who was the last person in there?
你回去  把坐便擦干净
You go back in there and you wipe the seat.
不要冲我的客人叫嚷
Hey, no nagging my customers!
你竟敢冲我老妈嚷嚷
Don't you yell at my mother!
你以为你是奈格特・克利斯蒂吗
What's that, Nagatha Christie?
琳达  亲爱的  这里你已经忙不过来了
Linda, sweetheart, you've got more than you can handle here.
我和你父亲决定再待一晚
Your father and I have decided to stay another night.
什么  不要啊
What?! No!
只要我们能帮上忙  会一直待下去
We'll stay as long as we need to.
不要  不要  不要  不要
No, no, no! No!
有人吗
Knock, knock.
谁啊
Who's there?
-我被留堂了  -真假啊
- I got detention. - Aw, come on.
真的  但我不想因为这个削我自己一顿
Yeah. But I don't wanna beat myself up about it,
这其实是老爸的错
since it's really dad's fault.
是因为你的历史报告
It's your history report. Yeah.
谢谢  妈妈  我们要
Thanks, mom. We're gonna...
你知道吗  我们需要你们
You know what? We're gonna need you.
我们要汲取周围一切救助
We'll take all the help we can get around here.
不  不  不  不  琳达  我要出去了
No, no, no. No. Linda, I'm gonna get out of here.
他们没必要留下来
They don't have to stay.
我有...  我有个主意
I have... I have an idea,
我刚想出来的新点子
a new idea I just thought of
想出了我该怎么立刻出去
on how I can get out right away.
天
Oh, boy.
婊子养的
ow! Son of a bitch!
他去哪了
Where did he go?
我能...  我能听到他的声音
I can... I can hear him.
-琳  -什么
- Lin... - Yeah?
我卡住了
I'm stuck.
是啊  我知道  鲍勃
Yeah, I know, Bob.
你不知道  我真的卡住了
No, I'm really stuck.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你是说你以前从来没被卡住过吗
Are you telling me you weren't stuck before?!
是啊
No.
你装蒜  你个骗子
You were fakin' it.
我不信
I can't believe this.
开心汉堡店
Bob's burgers.
琳达  我是泰迪
Hi, Linda. It's Teddy.
你好  泰迪
Oh, hi, Teddy.
我正在去救鲍勃的路上
Hey, I'm on my way over to get Bob out.
你猜怎么着  我们实际上
You know what? We actually
不需要你来救鲍勃出来
don't need you to come and get Bob out.
真的吗
Oh, really?
是的  他很好
Yeah, he's fine.
什么  不  我们...
What? No! We...
泰迪  泰...  我要...
Teddy! Te... we need...
我要出去
I need to come out!
再见  泰迪  泰迪
Bye, Teddy. Teddy!
在里面好好呆着吧
Have fun in there!
琳达
Linda!
第二天
好了  现在是我被困在墙里的第三天
Ok, day 3 stuck in the wall.
可以的话我很想去大个便
I sure would love to go poo.
那肯定很爽
That would be good.
好吧  爬是爬不出去了
Yep. Ok. I can't get out that way.
一个大刺扎我手里了
Ohh. I got a big splinter.
感觉有点晕
Uhh. Feel a little faint.
振作起来  鲍勃
Uhh. Keep it together, Bob.
到处都是蜘蛛  有没有
Are there spiders everywhere?
在我身上  在我身上
Aah! On me! On me! Aah! Spi...
你懂我的  对吗  小夜灯
You understand me, don't you, night light?
跟我说说  你为什么
Tell me. Why did you
想在你父母的餐厅里举行仪式
want to have a sance in your family's restaurant?
还有你父亲到底什么时候去世的
And when exactly did your father pass away?
我忘了
Uh, I forget.
把你的手给我
Give me your hands.
我们来召唤他的灵魂
Let's summon his spirit now.
如果有帮助的话  当然没问题
If that'll help,p, sure.
请你跟我一起哼
Ok. I need you to hum with me, please.
-跟你一起哼  -对
- Hum with you? -Yeah.
好大一扇门
Big door.
一直都有的吗
Was this always here?
这里居然有个地下酒吧
Wow. There's a speakeasy in the crawl space.
创意真好
What a great idea.
很高兴见到你  鲍勃先生
Nice to see you, Mr. Bob.
很高兴见到你  酷奇・科比
Nice to see you, Kuchi Kopi.
喝点什么  鲍勃先生
What'll it be, mr. Bob?
hooch指非法酿造的烈酒
给我来点烈酒  你们这儿最好的走私烈酒
Give me some hooch, your best bootleg hooch.
最近怎么样  鲍勃先生
How are things going, mr. Bob?
本来可以过得很好的  酷奇
Things could be better, Kuchi.
本来可以过得逍遥自在
Things could be a whole lot better.
你需要用洗手间吗  鲍勃先生
Do you need to use the facilities, Mr. Bob?
大号
Go number 2?
真高兴你问了  酷奇
I'm glad you asked, Kuchi.
是的  我的确得去趟大号
Yes, I do need to go number 2.
是的  我非常想去
Yes, I do, a lot.
这是我的创意
Here's my creation.
我把它叫做图纳米[海啸]
I call it the tunami.
这肯定会卖疯的
You're gonna sell a million of these.
味道棒极了
You know, that tastes so good,
我看就把它作为今天的推荐汉堡吧
I say we make it the burger of the day.
今日推荐  图纳米[海啸]
这么说你的丈母娘很任性
So your mother-in-law is quite willful.
没错
Yeah, she is.
得有人教导她一下
She needs to be corrected.
-什么意思  -杀了她
- What does that mean? -Killed.
你怎么变成了卑鄙的小夜灯了  酷奇
Wow. You turned into a mean little night light, Kuchi.
你知道你老婆和丈母娘
Did you know your wife and your mother-in-law
在干涉你的事业吗
are trying to interfere with your business?
是吗  我的事业
They are? My business?
她们企图引进一种
Yes. They are attempting to bring
外面的新品种进汉堡里
An outside protein into the situation.
外面的新品种
An outside protein?
-图纳[金枪鱼]  -金枪鱼
-Tuna. -Tuna?!
我好累
I'm so tired.
梦里全是姥爷  姥姥
My grandparents are haunting my dreams.
我得打个盹儿
I need a nap.
我可以爬到天花板上面  藏在里面睡觉
I could crawl up in the ceiling and sleep.
老爸就会这么做
That's what dad would do.
我会让他以我为傲的
Yeah. I'm gonna make him proud of me.
这真不错
Oh, it's nice up here.
伙计  你练过了
Man, you're ripped.
你肚子上的肌肉看起来像块结实的面包
Your abs look like challah bread.
谢谢  你看起来...
Thanks. You look...
天哪  男生的衣物间肯定就在那边
Oh, my god. The boys' locker room must be right over there.
我还是过会儿再睡吧
I'll sleep later.
有毒
Poison.
什么
What?
汞中毒
Mercury poisoning
金枪鱼里面
In the tuna fish!
鲍勃  别闹了
Bob, stop.
"Bob, stop."
学得很像  酷奇
good one, Kuchi.
你在跟谁讲话
Who are you talking to?
没什么  一个朋友而已
Oh, no one, just a friend.
他在里面快呆疯了
He's losing it in there.
好了  你是时候出来了
Ok, it's time for you to come out.
我出不来  琳达
There is no out, Linda,
现在出不来了  我在哪儿
Not anymore. Where am I?
在这儿吗  在这儿吗
Am I here, or am I here?
-鲍勃  -我无处不在
-Bob... -I'm everywhere!
我叫消防队了
I'm calling the fire department.
把毛巾摘了
drop the towel.
又来了  你听到了没
There it is again. Did you hear it?
把毛巾...
Drop the...
三兄弟姐妹在两天内都惹了麻烦
3 siblings in trouble in 2 days,
我要给你们个红旗
That's a red flag right there.
你们这是怎么了
What's going on with you guys?
我们的父亲被困在墙里了
Our father got trapped in the wall.
他那样死的吗
Is that how he died?
爸爸死了吗
Dad's dead?
被你搞砸了  福旺德老师
Good job, Mr. Frond.
我们本来打算在父亲节给她一个惊喜的
We were gonna tell her on father's day.
现在我们父亲节没什么事可做了
Now we have nothing to do on father's day!
好了  知道你们怎么了吗
Ok, you know what you are?
你们是危机儿童
You are kids in crisis.
我得家访一下了  今天就去
We need to conduct a home visit today.
-太好了  -好的  好的
-Yeah! -Ok. Ok.
我们现在就去
Let's get over there.
天哪  那是什么
Oh, my gosh. What are those?
忧郁玩偶
Grief puppets.
把它们带上  我们会用到的
Bring 'em. We're gonna need 'em.
那些呢  那些你带吗
What about those? Are you gonna bring those?
危机蜡笔  你说呢
Crisis crayons? You think?
危机蜡笔  绝对要带
Crisis crayons, absolutely.
我还有好多画要画呢
I've got so many drawings that I need to do.
不好意思
Hey, I-I'm sorry.
这边有点吵
It's a little loud in here.
你要来家访  什么时候
Y-you're coming for a home visit when?
就在那儿  动手吧
Right there. Chop.
别动手  我要呆在里面
Don't do it. I'm staying in here.
他疯了  动手吧
He's loopy. Chop.
我绝不出去
I'm never coming out!
这种情况我们见多了
Yeah, we see this all the time.
我来凿个洞  但有可能不够大
I'll chop a hole, but it's probably not gonna do it.
你得把一些吃的塞出来
You'll have to put some food out.
怎么回事
What's going on?
大概消防局接到尸臭弥漫的投诉
They probably got complaints about the smell
所以他们来把尸体从墙里弄出来
and came to get the body out of the wall.
你是说尸体还在那里吗
You mean it's still in there?
一部分吧
Well, parts of him.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
家难当头啊  福旺德先生
It's a real crisis, Mr. Frond!
没错  家难当头
Yeah. It's a crisis!
好棒哦  家难  我们家发生灾难了
Yeah! Crisis! We're all in crisis!
好吧好吧
All right! Okay!
你敢把我老爸从墙里整出来试试
Don't you take my daddy out of the wall!
鲍勃  学校的指导老师来做家访
Bob, I'm sitting here with the counselor from school
他以为你死了
who thinks you're dead,
这是你摆脱幼稚  为我分忧解难的好时机
so this would be a great time to grow up and help out.
指导老师  这又是什么  野营吗
A counselor? What is this, camp?
我在墙里玩得很开心
Heh heh heh. I'm funny in the wall.
我...
I... Ho! Ho! Ho! Ho! Ho! Ho! Ho! Ho!
你丈夫没死吗
Your husband is not dead?
没有  只是令人恼火而已
No, just aggravating.
好吧  那为什么露易丝说他已经死了
Okay, why would Louise let me think that he was dead?
她就喜欢捉弄她觉得傻逼兮兮的...
Oh, she just likes messing with people she thinks are stupid...
-那个啥  -啥  我...
- I know! - What? I...
来个汉堡怎么样
How about a burger?
想来点我们餐馆的美味吗  汉堡怎么样
Want something from the restaurant, a burger?
不了  我不吃肉
No. I don't eat meat.
杀了他
Kill him.
闭嘴  酷奇
Shut up, Kuchi.
鲍勃  我给你弄了些美味的牛肉末
I've got some nice ground beef for you, Bob.
鲍勃
Bob!
我现在整明白了
I'm starting to get a better picture here.
我现在正在查找
Right now I'm looking up guidelines for when and how
社会服务应介入此类案件的时机和方法
social services should get involved in a case like this.
-什么  -没错
- What?! - Yeah.
-社会服务  -没错
- Social services? - Yeah.
-你说什么  -你听到了
- What?! - Yeah!
那个清嗓的声音
That throat-clearing sound,
从墙壁中传来
it's coming from inside the wall!
鲍勃
Bob!
苍天啊
Oh, my God!
鲍勃  寻着我的声音过来
Bob, come towards my voice.
我可开喊了啊
I'll yell.
我妈妈来看我们
My mother's visiting us.
给我回来
Stop crawling away!
想都别想
This isn't happening!
抓到你了
Get ahold of yourself!
别摇我
Don't shake me.
摇得我想尿尿
I might go to the bathroom.
鲍勃  在这里
Here's Bobby.
我找到他了
I found him.
场面好激烈
That's hot!
25分钟后
感觉好多了
Much better.
boundaries: 心里学术语
指一个人将自己与周围其他人分辨开的能力
榜样糟糕  辨别意识模糊
Bad modeling, poor boundaries...
完全没有辨别意识
Well, really, no boundaries.
我得打几个电话
I'm gonna have to make some calls.
等一下  福旺德先生
Wait, Mr. Frond,
既然我的头脑清醒过来了
now that I have a clear head,
我就跟大家道个歉吧
I want to apologize to everybody.
躲在墙里的行为又自私又愚蠢
Hiding in the walls was selfish and dumb.
还有  琳达
And, Linda,
叫你奈格特・克利斯蒂  我很抱歉
I'm sorry I called you Nagatha Christie.
我头脑一时发热
It was in the heat of the moment,
做了傻事
and it was really dumb.
谢谢你  鲍勃
Aww. Thank you, Bobby.
斯皮罗・阿格纽是美国历史上第一位
由于刑事诉讼而辞职的副总统[于1973年辞职]
我是说  我可以表现得更勇敢的
I mean, I can do better,
就像斯皮罗・阿格纽一样
like Spiro Nagnew. Heh.
好了  见好就收吧
All right, quit while you're ahead.
碎碎念狂  安
Naggedy Ann?
那个碎碎念文化部长
Secretary of nagriculture?
这个搞笑
Ha! Now, that one's funny.
这个搞笑死了  我喜欢
That one's funny. I like... ha ha ha!
尽管我不碎碎念
I'm not a... not a nag.
但还是很搞笑  我喜欢
That's funny, though. I like it.
社会服务部吗
Social services?
给我等一下  小伙子
Now, hold on there, pal.
你结婚了吗
Are you married?
有小孩吗
You have kids?
都没有
No and no.
听我说
Listen to me.
我闺女是世界上最棒的妈妈
My daughter is the best mother in the world,
而他呢  他是个傻逼  但你知道吗
And this one, he is nuts. But guess what,
要是你养活一大家子  你也得变傻
having a family makes you go nuts.
所以如果你没有小孩
So if you don't have kids,
我认为你没有资格打电话叫谁来
I don't think you know enough to be calling in anyone.
事实上  我觉得你这熊样的
In fact, I don't think you come out
在我面前得得瑟瑟的就让我不爽
looking so good here yourself.
我怀疑你今天来做家访
I wonder if you even got permission from the school
都没有得到学校的许可
to come over here today.
他没有得到许可
He didn't.
他强行带我们离开课堂
He took us away from learning!
福旺德先生和我们坐在一辆车里
We were in the car with Mr. Frond,
但他并没有提醒我们系上安全带
and he didn't make us wear seat belts.
什么
What?!
赶紧把你的手机小本本踹兜里滚蛋
How about you put your phone and your little notebook back in your pocket there
少来管我们的事
and leave this family alone!
好的  淡定
Heh. Okay. All right.
淡定  淡定
All right. All right.
淡定
All right.
格罗瑞娅  谢谢你
Gloria, thank you.
2分钟后
欢迎您两位再来玩
Come back soon, you two.
姥爷姥姥再见
Bye, gram. Bye, gramps.
梦里见
See you in my dreams.
我得去整理一下屋子了
Well, I have a room to refart.
老爸  我的小夜灯可以还给我了吗
Dad, can I have my night light back now?
不行
No.
-还我  -不还
- Give it to me. - Stop it.
-这个夜灯是我的  -不还  就是不还
- It's my night light. - No. Stop.
这太让我难堪了
This is embarrassing to me.
不给  你都多大了啊
No! You're a grown man!
我要定了
I'm keeping it!